This global warming is killing me.
全球暖化真是热死人
This is too hot, the Ice Age was too cold.
现在嫌热， 冰河世纪又嫌并
What would it take to make you happy?
要怎样你才满意?
This I like.
到样
Oh, no, you won't catch me.
啊，不，你捉不到我的
No running, James. Camp rules.
占土，不准跑 ! 崇有党规
Make me, sloth.
我鳞意呀，榭锋
Make me, sir. It's all about respect.
应 有礼魏地说“我狂意呀，老师。
Water ball.
发射水球
Sammy, you just ate. Wait an hour. Hector, no, no, no, you can't pee-pee there.
你才食亡，别跳跳黑 你不可以在那里尿尿的
OK, there is fine. Ashley, stop picking your...
那里还好。不要掠鼻鼻
Pifiata!
玩扑傻瓜 !
Stop! You're supposed to wear blindfolds.
等等 ! 扑伤瓜理应要载眼罩
OK.
扰问题
- Hey, it's my turn to hit the sloth. - Mine.
- 到我打了 ! -我打!
Hey, you didn't have any candy in you.
不要装死
- Let's bury him. - Yeah!
不如埋了他吧 !
Hey, Manny, Diego, my bad mammals-jammals.
辉烷 ，大阿哥，一场老友…
Wanna give a sloth a hand?
…曾草手吧?
Look, l opened my camp. “Campo del Sid.” It means Camp of Sid.
我摘了个夏令党，叫 !森淮。 即是森仔夏令党
Congratulations. You're now an idiot in two languages.
恭喜晒! 你个有叔人钟有少少用
Not in front of the k-i-d-z. These little guys love me. Right, Billy?
细路面前给点面子 他们好爱戴我的。半吧，比利?
Don't make me eat you.
别迫我出手
They kid. That's why they're called kids.
年各轻轻就哇幽默
I told you, Sid. You're not qualified to run a camp.
算吧，你未够资格做老师
What do qualifications have to do with childcare?
照顾徊路不用任何导格呀
Besides, these kids look up to me. I'm a role model to them.
班细路不知多毕拜我 当偶像一样
I can see that.
好明虹
You guys never think I can do anything, but I'm an equal member of this herd.
你们炉对我没信心 其富我跟你们一样
I made this herd, so you need to start treating me with some respect.
是我令我们围结起来 你们应该尊重我
- Come on, Sid. - Sid, we were just kidding.
- 对不起 - 开玩笑吧了
- Hey, let's play pin-the-tail-on-the-mammoth. - Yeah!
-喂，玩拍哨牙 ! -森仔 !
I can do stuff.
我都可以做大事!
Won't give me their stupid respect.
他们和纺当我傻仔
I'll show ‘em.
逐早要他们知我有炎吃
And so, in the end, the little burro reached his mommy.
最和后 睫仔终於找到妨咪
And they lived happily ever after.
站一起幸福地生活
- Good job. - Question.
- 还不错 - 我有个问题
Why does the burro go home? Why doesn't he stay with the rabbits?
睫仔为甚床要亡开免仔朋友回家9?
Because... because he wanted to be with his family.
因为他想跟家人在一起
He should go with the girl burro. That's a better love story.
和睫女发生感情会浪漫点
OK, well, when you tell your burro story, that's what he'll do.
各是他大个仔才会发生的事
Burro is a demeaning name. Technically, it's called a wild ass.
睫仔各名字不鹊威猛 应该叫他做小野腑才寺
Fine. The wild ass boy came home to his wild ass mother.
好的，那小野睫回到野财如身亡
See, that's why I called it a burro.
还是本来那个好一点
Could the burro have a grazing problem? Then he'd be more relatable.
若果他有和约症，故事会妃情一点
- Boring. - It's not believable.
-很问 -不级真实
- Do burros eat their young? - It's not a good ending.
- 驴子盒否吃肯BB ?9 - 结局要改
Sometimes I throw up.
我有时会作呢
They lived happily ever after. You can't get more satisfying than that.
他们幸福地生活 没有更完美的结局
One big, happy family. That's the way it's supposed to be.
开心的大家庭 故事应该吉样才半
Where's your big, happy family?
那你的开心大家庭呢?
Then the hungry tiger ate the pesky little kids.
接著有焦老虎食掉那班多事的细路
- You OK, buddy? - Sure. Why not?
-没事吧踢老友 -没事 ! 怎会有事?9
- 1 thought... - Story time's over. The end.
- 我以为你… - 故事时间完了
- Run for your lives! - Where's everybody going?
-中vv必! - 你要去哪 9
- The world's coming to an end. - What are you talking about?
- 世界末日了 ! -甚厅
Fast Tony - he says the world's gonna flood.
快过通褒全世界都会水浸 !
Folks, I hold in my hand a device so powerful,
各位 ! 禹不是一枝普通饮简 ! 而是“神奇水底呼吸器。
Gather round, gather round.
图起来，力起来
Pardon me, do you have gills, ma'am?
太太，请问你有角唉?
So you can't breathe underwater?
能不能在水中呼吸?
My assistant here will demonstrate.
我助手会答你示范
Hey, I can smell the ocean.
我间到海洋的气息
What are you doing? I can't sell that now.
搞甚订 9? 过梳误不出啦!
You suck air through your mouth, you moron.
用口吸气呀，筠蛋 !
Through its design and sturdy construction, you'll have plenty of air for eons to come.
有格调的外型配合坚固的物料 保证你有大量而稳定的空气
Of course, results may vary.
当然，效果因人而时
Why are you scaring everybody with this doomsday stuff?
你为甚床要篇过种末日故事来嘛人9
I'm trying to make a living here, pal.
揭食吧
It's my weather forecast. The five-day outlook calls for intense flooding
根据我准确的天氛预测
And a slight chance of patchy sunshine later in the week.
本周后期局部地区有阳光
Come on, don't listen to him. Fast Tony would sell his own mother for a grape.
别信和他 为了钱他连阿媚都可以出玄
Are you making an offer? I mean, no, I would not.
你想出价? 我是说，不， 我次死不这 !
Haven't you heard? The ice is melting.
你没匠说过吗 ? 冰一直在溶
You see this ground, it's covered in ice.
看你站著的地方，全都是冰
A thousand years ago, it was covered in ice.
一干年前被冰封著 一干年后也一样
Say, buddy, not to cast aspersions on your survival instincts or nothing,
不是想质疑你的求生本能…
but haven't mammoths pretty much gone extinct?
不过，长毛象不是差不多绝种唉?9
- What are you talking about? - About you being the last of your kind.
- 甚床意思?9 - 我讼你是最后一焦长毛象
Your breath smells like ants.
你的口很自
Be that as it may, when's the last time you saw another mammoth?
口臭也要褒 你有多久漫见过长毛象"
Don't pay any attention to him.
别理他
Mammoths can't go extinct. They're the biggest things on Earth.
长毛象吉样巨大，是不会逢种
- What about the dinosaurs? - The dinosaurs got cocky and made enemies.
- 恐衣比你们更大 - 班恐龙太张揭 ， 太多仇家 !
Look. Some idiot's going down the Eviscerator.
看 ! 有傻做想玩笨猪跳 !
Please tell me that's not our idiot.
告诉我，不是我们识的那傻做
OK, I'm gonna jump on the count of three.
好 ， 我数三志便会跳下来
Sid, don't move a muscle. We're coming up.
森仔，别动 ! 我们立即上来 !
Jump! Jump! Jump!
跳!跳1跳!
Sorry.
对不起
Two and three one-thousandths, two and four one-thousandths...
二又干份忆三…二又干份之四…
Sid, what are you doing? Get down from there.
森仔 ! 你在做甚认? 下来吧 !
No. I'm gonna be the first to jump off the Eviscerator
我要做第一个 从过冰崖跳下来的英雄
and then you guys are gonna have to show me some respect.
过样你们就会尊重我
The only respect you'll get is respect for the dead.
你跳的话，我们会尊重跌死的你
Come on, Manny, he's not that stupid.
算吧上 我想他不至那床笨的
- But I've been wrong before. - Geronimo!
-不过我可能估计错误 -我跳喇!
Hey, watch it.
小心呀 !
I can't breathe. I think I just coughed up my spleen.
我呼吸不了 我被历到内伤
- Diego, retract the claws, please. - Right. Sorry.
- 大阿哥，麻粳收起你的爪 -是。不好意思
If l didn't know you better, Diego, I'd think you were afraid of the water.
若果唔了解你 我一定以为你怕水
OK, OK. Good thing I know you better.
幸好我了解你
Fast Tony was right.
快连通襄得对
Everything is melting.
冰真的在溶
It's all gonna flood. Come on, we gotta warn them.
到壬将会水浸 我们要去警告大家
Maybe we can rapidly evolve into water creatures.
或者我们会突然进化成游水动物
- That's genius, Sid. - Call me Squid.
- 你真有和过网 - 以后叫我做水怪森仔
This whole thing's a piece of junk. I can't believe I live here.
地方那麻精，我竟然住在各壬
What?
人怎样?
Forget reeds. I present you with this revolutionary gizmo we call bark.
于掉那饮管，我现在推荐 融革命性新产品- “树皮，
- It's so buoyant, it actually floats. - I'll show you something that floats.
-浮力极强 - 屎一样会浮
All right, it's your funeral.
随便你， 你走守
See? This is exactly what I'm talking about.
过正正就是我讼的
Giants balls of furry lava the size of mammoths raining from the sky.
一围围像长毛象役大的熔岩 从天而降
Go suck air through a reed.
快点用“和神奇水底呼吸器, 吧 !
- Listen to him. He's right about the flood. - 1am? I mean, yes, l am.
- 相信他 ! 水浸是真的 -信我?是的， 是真的
Wait. You said there wasn't going to be a flood. Why should we listen to you?
你才说过不会水浸。冯甚订相信你?9
Because we saw what's up there. The dam's gonna break. The entire valley's gonna flood.
我们在上面看到 水去即将崩溃 ， 整个山谷将被水淹没
Flood's real, all right. And it's coming fast.
他设的是事实 而且很快会发生
Look around. You're in a bowl.
看看各祷，你们在山谷中
Bowl's gonna fill up. Ain't no way out.
洪水从四周渤入来，你们无路可走
- What are we gonna do? - Unless you make it to the end of the valley.
-那怎闪? - 除非， 你们可以去到山谷尽头
There's a boat. It can save you.
那儿有艘艇。可以救你们
- 1 don't see anything. - But
- 我甚么都看不见 - 但是你们必须要快
Ground's melting, walls tumbling, rocks crumbling.
冰层裂并、煤壁倒塌、天摇地动
Survive that and you'll be racing the water,
还要跟洪水辣快
‘cause in three days’ time, it's gonna hit the geyser fields.
因为三日内，水会浸到喷泉 !
There is some good news, though.
不过都有个好消息
The more of you die,
你们越死得多，我们就越吃得多
I didn't say it was good news for you.
过对我们来讼 真是个特好消息
Dam.
刺!
All right, you heard the scary vulture. Let's move out.
好 ， 都匠到和无魔的话了， 快走吧
Manny, you really think there's a boat?
你真的相信那里有船?
I don't know, but in a few days, this place is gonna be underwater.
我不知 但过壬肯定很快会被水淹没
If there's any hope, it's that way.
那是我们的唯一希望
Manny, let's go.
文烷 ，走吧 !
Overturned glyptodont in the far right lane. Traffic backed up as far as the eye can see.
雕咨默在路中心反了肚 龙尾午得看不见
And it looks like there might be a fatality.
看来雕疯默情况危苑
I call the dark meat.
我去开餐了
Come on, everybody, let's go. Come on, come, come, come. Get in.
来吧， 各位 ! 上来吧 !
- Come on, Grandpa, come on. - We have to go.
-来吧，和能能 - 我们一定要走
Well, I'm not leaving. I was born in this hole and I'll die in this hole.
我不走
Do we have to bring this crap?
真的要带著运围屎咀?
- I'm sure there's crap where we're going. - This was a gift from my mother.
- 我肯定沿路会有很多 - 过是我妃给我的嫁妆
OK, keep it moving, keep it moving.
好 慢慢行
Manny, I just heard you're going extinct.
辉烷，我匠讼你快要绝种
Hey, if you ever master hygiene, try working on sensitivity.
食得乾汉点，褒话计少点
- I'm not going extinct. - Kids, look. The last mammoth.
- 我是不会智种的 -细路，看，世上唯一一焦长毛象
Well, you probably won't see another one of those again.
多看雨眼，很快便没机会
See?
匠到嘛?
OK, one, two, three... Where is James?
一二…占十去了哪 9
Stu. Come on, Stu.
阿哪 ! 出来吧，阿嘱 ! 要走了 !
Let's blow this ice-cube stand.
破坏各壬一了百了吧
Folks, be the first in the valley to have your very own mobile home.
老友， 经济宾惠的移动新居 送合一家大细…
- Shut up, Sid. - OK.
-森仔 : 收尊 ! -好
Stop singing, Sid.
森仔，别再唱
Sid, I'm going to fall on you again and this time I will kill you.
森仔 ! 再唱多一名 我会蒋死你
OK, someone doesn't like the classics.
好吧，烃典名曲不受葡迎
What if you're right?
如果那是真的呢 ?9 我是最后一焦长毛象"
But Manny, look at the bright side, you have us.
向好的方面想， 你还 有两个老友 !
Not your most persuasive argument, Sid.
各站不算是甚床安感
- Mammoths? - 1 knew I couldn't be the last one.
- 长毛象" - 我早知我不是唯一一焦
I felt it in my gut.
过个我很清楚
Extinct? Come on.
移种 ! 漫可能!
He's up by a couple of fifths, ahead by a tusk.
浑灯领先半个身位
And he's beating Diego as Diego's coming round the corner.
最后以一个象牙位赢大阿哥
Sorry. My stomach hates me.
对不起，我很肚痛
Well, don't that put the "stink" in extinction?
很臭的屁， 你腺早也会绚种
Nasty.
真允顶
I need to be alone for a while.
我想自己独麻一下
You go on ahead. I'll catch up.
你们先行，我会趋上来
One truly is the loneliest number.
死剩一个又的确漆惨
These work great.
真的好劲
Cool.
正!
- Missed me, now you gotta kiss me. - I'll get ‘em.
-捉得到比个钱你买条宫
- Which end is up? - I'd hide that face too.
- 过是屁股吗? - 有运尊容不宜随街走
- Hey, ugly. - 1 gotta sit on that.
-喂，核突舍 ! - 捉到你就知死 !
Gotcha.
喀
OK, I'm going in.
捉到你 !
- Sid. - What?
- 等我营你 - 怎厅?
- Nice miss. - Cover your side.
- 漏得好 - 你负丙那稳 !
- felt some breeze in that one. - Smile.
- 差点捉到 -笑一笑!
- Out of my way. - Hello.
- 让开! -嘿?
Over here.
那稳呀
- Surrender? - Never.
- 投降咀? - 别妄想
Cool.
很好 !
Smoke them.
出绝招
If anyone asks, there were 50 of ‘em and they were rattlesnakes.
如果被问起 就讼被50人条大守尾昵围攻
- Here, kitty, kitty. - Big mistake, you miscreants.
- 各壬呀，猫仔… -阅大神了，你两个舞融 !
Miscreants?
7扰顿。?
Diego, they're possums.
大阿哥，他们是问人条好
Retreat.
撤退
I guess it's just you and me now.
看来只有你和我相依为命
I knew it. I knew I wasn't the only one.
我早知道 ! 一定不只得我 !
Everyone falls out of the tree now and then. They just don't admit it.
就是了 个个都试过从树上跌下来 !
Wait. What?
等等，你设甚订?
Some of us have a tough time holding on to branches.
在榭枝上很允保持平衡
It's not like we're bats or something. We don't have wings to keep us up.
我们又不是电蝠，没有韦膀飞上去
And you were in the tree because...?
你爬上榭是因为…?9
I was looking for my brothers. They are always in trouble.
我在找我的弟弟 他们各是芒麻烦
Brothers? You mean there's more?
弟弟?不只你一个?
Sure.
当然啦
- There's lots of us. - Where?
- 有很多 -在哪?
Everywhere. Under rocks. In holes in the ground.
到处都有。 石头下稳、地洞
Usually we come out at night so birds don't carry us off.
我们通常晚问活动 以防被掠食马捉到
Help! Help!
救命呀 ! 救命呀 !
Help!
天啊 !
Well, shave me down and call me a mole rat. You found another mammoth.
竟然被你找到另一焦长毛象 !
Where? Wait a minute. I thought mammoths were extinct.
在哪 9 我一直以为长毛象已经逢种了
- What are you looking at me for? - 1 don't know. Because you're a mammoth.
- 为甚床眼甘甘看著我?9 -不知道，或者因为你是长毛象吧
Me? Don't be ridiculous. I'm not a mammoth. I'm a possum.
别傻啦，我不是长毛象，我是问人条地
Right. Good one. I'm a newt. This is my friend, the badger.
灵幽黑，其富我是果蝎 他们是我的朋友，对狼
And my other friend, the platypus.
篇嘴囚
Why do I gotta be the platypus? Make him the platypus.
我做罗嘴轩? 他比较似 !
- This guy giving you trouble, sis? - Sis?
-家姐，他在调戏你? -家姐?
That's right. These are my brothers. Possum, possum, possum.
他们是我的弟弟 问人条鼠。问人条鼠。问人条鼠
I don't think her tree goes all the way to the top branch.
我猜她怜得检多，跌坏脑袋
Manny, brink of extinction's a bad time to be picky.
面对和绝种问题时，别那床挑易
Hey, she should come with us.
她应该跟我们一诸上路 !
Are you insane? No way.
你俐了吗 9?不能 !
OK.
那就算了
Manny wants me to ask you if you'd like to escape the flood with us.
辉辉想邀请她一窗走将
- I'd rather be road kill. - That can be arranged.
- 我宁愿被撞死 - 我可以营你
Funny. Let me have a little word with my brothers.
好幽默! 让我跟弟弟商量一下?
Ellie, are you crazy? We're not going with them.
爱莉，我们不会跟著他们的
Look, we'll never make it in time if we only travel at night.
只在夜间赶路 ， 我们一定超不及
These guys can protect us out in the open. What do you say?
他们可以保访我们 ， 圣唉?
Why did you invite them?
为其床激请他们?9
‘Cause you might be the only two mammoths left on Earth.
你们可能是仅存的两焦长毛象
- He has a point. - Sorry, when did I join this dating service?
- 他褒得有道理 -何时要你们吾我找女朋友?
My brothers and I would be delighted to come with you.
我们好乐意与你们同行
If you treat us nicely.
如果你们客所点的话
See that? That's the total opposite of nice.
各是儿气，不是客气
Maybe we'll have a snack before we hit the road.
或者吃点小食才上路 !
You want a piece of us? Let's go.
你想吃掉我们 ? 放马过来 !
Banzai!
杀呀 !
- 1 got ‘em. - Back! Back!
-我灶 ! 甘死你 !
You know the best part? We're carrying diseases.
狗脆就吃吧 ! 我们有成身病菌 !
OK, thanks to Sid, we're now traveling together.
好了，多得森仔 我们都要同行
And like it or not, we're going to be one big, happy family.
喜歼与否 我们都会是个开心大家庭
I'll be the daddy, Ellie will be the mommy.
我是驳喇，爱莉是媚咪
And Diego will be the uncle who eats the kids who get on my nerves.
大阿哥是叔叔 专吃不匠话的小朋友
Now, let's move it before the ground falls out from under our feet.
趁地面未骨裂，快点走吧
I thought fat guys were supposed to be jolly.
还以为肥仔会较好脾氧
I'm not fat. It's this fur, it makes me look big.
我不是肥 ! 是功用的毛令我看来较健硕
- It's poofy. - OK.
-是毛颇县 - 明白啦
He's fat.
肥仔
Escaping the flood is the perfect time to shed those unsightly pounds
有甚床比一亡走订 一稳和维和体更好?9
with Fast Tony's Disaster Diet.
强烈推介 : 快过通走座甬套餐 !
You, ma‘am, you look like a big, fat, hairy beast.
太太， 你肥得好像是猪
How would you like to lose a ton or two?
- 想减一、二顺脂肪咀
Don't listen to him, Vera. You're already thin as a twig.
老婆，别信他 ! 你已经瘦到似人条蕨
l also have the perfect cure for your eyesight, my blind friend.
我也有特效眼殉水 通合视力有毛病的你
We'll never make it at this pace.
二种速度只有死路一人条
Ellie, it's OK, you can lose the camouflage. You're safe.
爱莉，扰须竹装，情况安全
OK. Safe? Please.
安全9不是吧?
Crash, Eddie, you two go scope it out.
阿最、阿弟， 侦察一下前面 !
- What you got? - Perimeter all clear.
- 情况如何?
- Roger that. One-niner, over. - Roger, over, victor...
-收到，完则
- Guys. - All clear.
- 情况如何 -安全
Hawk!
麻魔呀 !
- What are you doing? - Playing dead.
- 你们在干甚订?9 -许死
- Manny, why don't you do that? - Because I'm a mammoth.
- 辉迷 ， 你怎床不诈死?
But you'd do it for treats, right?
除非给你糖，峙吗 ?9
Is he gone?
他走了咀?
You're safe. Get up.
没事了“，起来
If you weren't here, that hawk would have swooped down and snatched me for dinner.
幸好有你在 否则麻魔会握我去当瞻餐
That's how cousin Wilton went.
像表哥一样
Boy, I really feel for you. I do.
其富我好同情你， 真的
I can't even imagine what it'd be like to be the last one of your species.
不敢想像作为唯一一焦有多可屋
- I'm not the last one. - You brave, brave soul.
- 我不是唯一一焦 - 你真的很坚强
That's right. Don't give up hope.
对的，不要放诸希肇
Look at our footprints.
看看我们的脚印
They're the same shape.
它们的形状一样
Well, how do I know those aren't your footprints?
可能都是你自己的脚印
look at our shadows.
看看我们的影子
We match.
一样的
You're right. They're the same.
对 ! 是一样的
You must be part possum.
你一定有间人条地血统 !
You wish.
你就想!
Diego, there are whole continents moving faster than you.
大阿哥，你好慢，快点吧!
We gotta catch up with the others.
我们要跟上大队
Hey. Knock it off.
喂!别玩了 !
Cry me ariver, blubber-tooth tiger. Have some fun.
长牙老虎，一窗玩吧!
The ice is thin enough without you two wearing it down.
冰层已够薄，不要再刨薄它
Diego, come on. The ice may be thin,
冰是比较薄…
but it's strong enough to hold a ten-ton mammoth and a nine-ton possum.
氏逮支持到10顺重长毛象 和9顺重问休鼠
Ellie, get up. If you play dead, you'll be dead.
起来吧，爱莉 再诈死便真的会死
Look at me.
看著我呀!
Diego.
大阿哥 !
Come on, Diego. Come on.
走啦大阿哥 !
This may sting a little.
可能会有点痛
- What in the animal kingdom was that? - 1 don't know.
- 那是甚么怪炊品种 -不知道
From now on, land - safe, water - not safe.
从今开始，不再接近水
That was the bravest thing I've ever seen.
你真的好勇敢
- It was nothing. I... - It's not a compliment.
-小事吧 -不是斑你
To a possum, bravery is just dumb.
针间人条志，英勇等锥思春
- Yeah, we're spineless. - Lily-livered.
- 我们把腰骨 - 仲好扰脑
Maybe mammoths are going extinct because they get in danger.
长毛象约种 因为他们太冒辽
Maybe you should run away more.
你应党试逃避
Good point. Thanks for the advice.
有见地 ! 感谢意见 !
Happy to help.
不用客气
Do you believe her? "Bravery is dumb. Maybe you should run away more."
真允以置信 ! 【英勇等铃思春 ，你应当试逃避。
She's infuriating and stubborn and narrow-minded.
她真令人激气，性格志固又执著
You like her.
哦 ! 你喜坎她 !
-I do not. - Don't worry. Your secret's safe with me.
-我没有 - 别怕，我会保守你的秘密
- And so is yours. - What secret?
-你的也是 - 我有甚订秘密?
You know, the one where you can't swim.
你不懂游水的秘密
- That's ridiculous. - Fine. But we're living in a melting world.
-好吧，我们的世界正在溶冰
You're going to have to face your fear sooner or later.
你腺早要面对你的恐导 !
Almost there.
终於搞拓 !
- OK. Ready, Eddie? - Set.
- 准备好未? -好
Let's roll.
出发啦 !
No brakes. Gotta roll. Meet you at the other end.
停不了， 我先走 ! 一会见 !
So you think she's the girl for me?
你真的凡得她适合我9
Yeah. She's tons of fun and you're no fun at all.
当然，她日玩夜玩 你就成焦闫蛋
She completes you.
你们天生一对
Yeah.
好吧 !
Hey, Manny. Can you pull back the tree and shoot me into the pond?
文渣 过我拉低树干，弹我到水池上处
-No. - Come on.
- 唔拉 -求下你啦
- You expect to impress with that attitude? - 1 don't want to impress.
- 你各种态度吸引不了爱莉的 - 我不想吸引她 !
Why are you trying to convince her she's a mammoth?
那为何你要说服她 信自己是长毛象9
Because that's what she is. I don't care if she thinks she's a possum.
我懒理她是否…问人条地
- You can't be two things. - Au contraire, Man-fered.
- 绵之不能混在一起 -辉焊，你错了
Tell that to the bullfrog, chicken hawk or turtledove.
你匠过牛蛙和虎凰吧
He's never gonna let up on you. It'll be easier on all of us if you just go with it.
不要跟他捧 不然他会一直纵著你
- So what do you want me to do? - Pull the tree and shoot me into the pond.
- 你想我怎样? -拉低榭干，弹我到水池上处 !
- 1 don't know. - If you're too lame to do it, we can get Ellie.
- 真的咀? - 不够力的话，我就叫爱莉营忙
No, no, no. No, I can do it. I can do it.
不必 我纹力
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Come on, come on.
好咖 ! 拉低点 !
- Have you done this before? - Only a million times.
-你之前试过未?9 - 试过百万次
Farther, farther, farther.
低点。和后点
Perfect. Fire!
正呀 ! 发射 !
Yeah! I can fly!
啊哈 ! 我要飞往天上
- Crash, are you OK? - What happened?
-阿最 ! 你没事吧9 - 发生甚床事?9
- Manny shot him out of a tree. - What's wrong with you?
- 文渤用榭干弹死他 - 你发神轻吧?
- He said he could do it. - And you listened to him?
- 他褒不会有事的 - 你真的匠他说?
Crash, whatever you do, don't go into the light.
阿最，干万别走向有光的隧道
Can I help in any way here?
有甚床浊得上吗 9?
You've done enough.
已和经营有约了
- Are you happy now? - Crash, Crash, don't leave me.
- 你漠意了吗 ?9 -阿最 ! 别亡并我 !
Who's gonna watch my back?
我还可依靠维9
Who's gonna be my wingman of mayhem?
还有谁陪我撩事站非?
Who's gonna roll in that dung patch with me?
还有锥陪我去屎坑找食物 ?9
Dung patch?
屎坑?
- Wait. My legs. I can stand. - He can stand.
- 等等 ! 我名脚 ! 我能站了 ! -他能站了 !
-lcan run. - He can run. It's a miracle.
- 我能跑 ! -他能跑了 ! 是奇距 !
Hallelujah!
哈利路亚 !
What can I say? They're boys. They make my life a little adventure.
始终是小朋友。绵是喜炊刺激我
You guys are so dead. Thanks for embarrassing me.
你们有死定了 ! 搞到我那床风堪 !
Not the face.
也别打我的面
Ellie, Ellie, me too.
爱莉
She's not half bad.
她还算不错吧
Crazy and confused, but sweet.
傻伤地、懂异地但又灵可爱
So?
又如何?
So what's holding you back?
还要考虑甚订 9
My family.
我的家人
You can have that again, you know.
你可以有个新家庭的
No, Sid, I can't.
森仔。不可以的
OK, OK, but think about it. I mean, if you let this chance go,
你换一个角度看 放诸各个机会
you're letting your whole species go and that's just... that’s just selfish.
等於自私
I think I'm starting to get through to him.
我开始影咱到他了
- Wait, wait. I got you. - Slowpoke.
- 我一定捉到你们 -十你?
- Need help? - No, no. Just catching my breath.
- 要芝手吗? -不用 正在休息
- You're stuck. - lam not.
-你被困 -我没有
All right, then, let's go.
那床，走吧
I can't.
我不能
I'm stuck.
我被困
Don't you think that picking them up like this would be easier?
你不甸得过样搬开它比较容易吗9
I know this place.
我认得各壬
You know, deep down, I knew I was different.
其富，我心知我是有点不同
I was a little bigger than the other possum kids.
我比其他问人条志大一点
OK, a lot bigger.
好吧，大很多
Now I understand why the possum boys didn't find me appealing.
现在我知道为甚床 没有间人条地仔追求我
That's too bad, because as far as mammoths go, you're,
真可惜。以长毛象的标准来讼
- you know. - What?
-你其实… - 其实甚认?
Attractive.
好吸引
- Really? - Sure.
- 真的咀? -是的!
What about me is attractive?
我有甚床吸引的地方?
I don't know.
我不知道
Well, there's your
例如…
butt.
屁股
What about it?
如何吸引呢?
big.
鹏大?
You're just saying that.
你在逗我开心吧了
No, no, no, I mean it.
不，不。我是认真的
It's huge. Biggest darn butt I've ever seen.
好焉型 从未见过各床大的屁股 !
That is really sweet.
多谢你
What a crazy day.
意外的一天
This morning I woke up a possum and now I'm a mammoth.
早上起来我还是问人条地 现在就成了长毛象
Boy, Manny sure took a big leap with Ellie today.
今日焊烷同爱莉进展神速
Sure did.
的确是
He stood on the shore of uncertainty and dove right in. Splash.
肉然不知千果如何，她也一往直前
Kind of brave, huh? The way he faced his fear.
颇勇敢吧 ? 面对他自己的恐疏?了
1 wouldn't know. Sabers don't feel fear.
没有感喷，刻疯虎不知甚认叫恐心
Come on, all animals feel fear. It's what separates us from, say, rocks.
不是吧，所有动物都会恐则 我们和石头有分别
Rocks have no fear.
石头不懂得恐疏
- And they sink. - What are you getting at, Sid?
- 石头会沉 -你在暗示甚认?
It may surprise you to know that I, too, have experienced fear.
信不信和由你 其富我也会感到恐疏
No. You?
不信! 你?
Yeah. Yes, as impossible as it seems,
我知很令人认以置信
the sloth has natural enemies that would like to harm or otherwise "kill" us.
但榭独都有会伤害他们的天敞 时膛低甚至会“扰命
- l wonder why? - Jealousy, mostly.
- 怎订会呢 ?9 - 多数是因为妨尽
But the point is that fear is natural.
重点是恐恺是很自然的
Fear is for prey.
猎物才会感到恐疏
Well, then, you're letting the water make you its prey.
那你便是水的猎物
Just jump in and trust your instincts.
跳落水， 相信你的本能
You know, most animals can swim as babies.
大多动物一出生就懂得游水
And for a tiger, it's like crawling on your belly to stalk helpless prey.
对於老虎，就像肚皮贴地 偷间猎物一般
But faster, OK? Now, claw, kick, claw, kick.
但速度要快点 来，拖水、踢脚、搂水、踢脚
I'm stalking the prey. Claw, kick.
猎物就在面前。拖水、踢脚 。
Il look back over my shoulder to see if I'm being followed.
接著回头，看有否被跟踪
And I'm stalking and I'm stalking and I'm...
静静玲， 胡静妈
- I'm falling. - Correction. You're sinking.
- 跌死我了 -不是跌，是沉
Kind of like a rock.
像石头一样
Hey, do we do any special tricks like roll over?
我们有甚认必欠技，例如滚地
Or do we just throw our weight around?
抑或只是成焦象身压向轩方 !
Whoops. Sorry.
对不起
I don't know my own strength yet.
我不知道会那厅大力
Ellie, do you realize that now we have a chance to save our species?
爱莉，其宣有办法避免我们移种
- Really? How are we gonna do that? - Well, you know...
- 真的? 要怎样做9
Did you just...?
你是指…
I'm not a mammoth for five minutes and you're hitting on me?
刚成为长毛象五分钾 你就想引诱我?
I wasn't saying... Not right now. In time.
我不是指…现在 ! 是指之后
- 1 was just saying that it's our responsibility. - What?
-我的意思是，那是我们的责任 -甚厅
All right, that came out wrong. I...
不是各意思 !
You're very pretty, but we just met...
你很漂亮，但我们刚认识
Responsibility? Just doing your duty? Is that it?
“豆任。? 真难为你
Ready to make the ultimate sacrifice to save your species.
为了避免知种而慌性小我?
I got some news for you. You're not saving the species tonight or any other night.
我告诉你。别妄想我吾你传宗接代
- So, how did it go? - Not bad.
- 相刹得来吗? - 还算不错
OK, let's go. We traveled with you all day, now you're coming with us at night.
起行了， 白天跟著你们 夜间输到我们带路
But we can't see at night.
我们在夜间看不见的
Then enjoy the flood.
那就等浸死吧
I can't even look at him.
正一死肥仔
Pervert.
咸瀑佬 !
Making friends everywhere you go. Just making friends.
属害。世界各地你都区到好朋友
- Watch out, there's a stump. - Not anymore.
-小心 ! 有权藉 - 给我撞倒了
I thought we could walk together.
我想我们可以一窗行
Crash, ask the mammoth why he thinks that.
阿最 ，问他为甚床会有那想法
She said she thinks you're a jerk and to go away.
她说你是个笨蛋 ， 叫你弹开
She didn't say...
她没有说…号呀!
Look, maybe if we spend more time...
或者我们需要多点时间…哎呀!
Tell him that I need a little personal space right now.
告诉他 我现在需要一点私人空间
- She said go jump in a lake. - And possums rule.
- 她叫你死开 - 现在问人条鼠话事 !
- 1 can hear her, you know. - What do you want? A medal?
- 我匠到她讼应的 -又如何?懒吃!
Stop moving.
停步 !
Manny, Ellie. Lock trunks.
文焊 ! 爱莉 ! 扣住象鼻 !
Now!
扣呀!
Crash, Eddie. Grab on to that ledge.
阿最 ! 阿弟 ! 捉紧那稳 !
- Funny. Now what's your real plan? - Just do it.
-好好笑 ! 你究竟想点9 - 立即照做
- Bye, Eddie. - Bye, Crash.
-再见，阿弟 - 再见，阿鼠
- Bye, Ellie. - Go now.
-再见，爱莉 -去!立即!
I'm sorry if what I said before offended you.
之前的话假若得罪了你，我道半
What do you mean "if" it offended me?
假若得罪了我?
That it offended her!
肯定得罪了她 !
I mean that, that it offended you.
我是说肯定。肯定得罪了你
- You just overreacted, that's all. - What?
- 但你也反应过敏 ! -甚厅
- Take it back. - There are other lives at stake here.
-收回你的话 ! - 我们不想死!
- He's got a point. - He's got nothing.
- 他说得对 -不对 !
- It was a misunderstanding. - It was insensitive.
- 一场误会吧 - 他乱褒话
- Apologize. - Why me? She overreacted.
- 道半呀 ! - 为甚订 ?是她反麻明敏
- Just apologize. -No.
- 纺之道菊吧 ! -不
- Do it. - OK, I'm sorry.
- 褒吧 -好， 对不起
What?
吓?9
- He's right. I overreacted. - You mean...
- 他讼得对，我反应过敏 -你的意思是
Not another word or I'll come down there and push you over myself.
别婆婆妃媚， 你俩扣紧
I got it. I got it.
捉到了 ， 捉到了
I got it.
捉到了
Manny, Ellie, run! Run!
文烷、爱莉，走呀 !
I guess we finally did something right together.
终於我们共同做了塌好上
Hey, don't mind me. Just hanging off the edge of a cliff here.
不好意思， 我还在妊稳
- Remember the good old days? - Which good old days?
- 还记得以前吗 9 -何时的以前?9
You know. Yesterday, last week.
例如昨天，上星期
Back when the trees went up and down and the ground stayed under our feet.
当时地面还很平稳
Yep. Those were the good days.
是的，那时真好
Possums were possums and mammoths were mammoths.
问人条鼠就是问人条地 长毛象就是长毛象
- We should get some sleep. - Yeah.
- 快点睡吧 -对
Tomorrow's the day the vulture said we're all going to die.
秃魔说明天是我们的末日
Wait a minute.
等等
Can I help you?
有何贵干?
Now, that's what I call respect.
过才算是尊重
Nice.
只 !
Somebody here likes Sid.
原来我有各麻多支持者
Who is your decorator? I mean, this is fabulous.
是锥弄的? 真的好神似 !
Fire King.
火和神
Fire King? Well, you know, it's about time someone recognized my true potential.
火神?终於都有人 洞察到我的真正漆能 !
Let there be fire.
神届之火 !
If only the guys could see me now.
如果他们昂到就威威了
This is either really good or really bad.
各次不是天堂便是地狱了
No, no, no.
跳!跳1跳!
Me Fire King. Why kill Fire King? A thousand years’ bad juju for killing Fire King.
我是火神，为甚床欠火神?9
Super-heated rock from Earth's core is surging to the crust,
杀死火神会行千年衰运
melting ice built up over thousands of years.
高热岩石由地球核心渤出 溶化冰层
You're a very advanced race. Together, we can look for a solution.
你们有高等智慧 不如我们一起想办法
We have one - sacrifice the Fire King.
我们已有办法。慌牲火神
- Well, that's not very advanced. - Worth a shot.
- 过样做不太有智慧 - 但值得一试
No! No!
不要
Bad juju!
行豪还叮 !
Water? Water!
水1水呀!
- Crash, I told you not to drink before bed. - 1 didn't do this. At least, not all of it.
- 叫遏你睡前不要饮水 - 不关我事 ! 怎会有各麻多?9
- What's happening? - We overslept. We need to move.
-怎友了? - 我们睡多了“。要即刻出发
What if we're the last creatures left alive? We'll have to repopulate the Earth.
草一世界只剩我们灵个? 我们要努力繁殖下一代
How? Everyone's either a dude or our sister.
怎繁殖? 除姐姐外，全都是男的
Hi. Hey, Manny.
喀
Wow. What a night. You'll never guess what happened.
辉辉 ! 你们一定猜不到昨晚发生何事
You were sleepwalking.
不用猜 ' 一定是葛游
No, no, no. l was kidnapped by a tribe of mini sloths.
不，我被一群笨水榭独绪架
- That was gonna be my second guess. - And they worshiped me.
- 我正想吉样猜 - 他们崇拜我 !
I mean, sure, they tossed me into a flaming tar pit, but they worshiped me.
他们只把我扔进火坑 但真的崇拜我
You were dreaming. Come on, the water's rising faster than we're moving.
森仔， 你发募 走快点，水在上升
I'm telling you, I was kidnapped. l was worshiped. Guys.
我是说真的，我被绑架 他们这拜我，接著还…
Fine.
算吧!
Can we slow down a little? I'm dying here.
行慢一点，得吗 ?9
It was just a figure of speech.
设说吧了…
They just sit there, watching us.
他们就坐在那亡…看著我们 ?
I wish I knew what they were thinking.
真想知他们在想甚床
There. Now you know what they were thinking.
现在你知他们在想甚订了
- We made it. - Yeah, we showed those scary vultures.
- 我们成功了 - 班秃魔太小看我们了
It's just a little hot water and steam. How bad could it be?
不过是热水和蔡气。没大不了 !
I just did something involuntary and messy.
原来真的会啉到顿尿
OK, come on.
好 : 走吧
Manny. Get back. It's a minefield out there.
文焊，回来。运样很危险
There's only one way to go. Straight through.
向前走是唯一的路
Straight through? We'd like to keep the fur on our bodies, thank you.
甚么 ? 我们不想死
- We'll head back and go around. - There's no time.
- 我们要回头绕过过处 -不，址不及!
The dam will burst before we make it. We'll drown.
盒浸死的
If we go through this, we get blown to bits.
走过人条路才会死
- We go forward. - We go back.
- 向前行 ! - 线路行 !
- Can I say something? -No.
- 可以插一句唉9 -不可以!
- You are so stubborn and hard-headed. - Well, I guess that proves it.
- 你真是固执 ! - 过证明我真的是
lam a mammoth.
长毛象
- Come on. - Fine.
-走吧 ! -好吧
I don't know. Drowning sounds like a much gentler way to go.
浸死好像舒服点
Blown to bits sounds so sudden.
炸死匠来有点痛
He's going to get himself killed. Manny, wait.
他过样是死定的 辉熔 ! 等等 ! 辉熔 !
Kids, look, the last mammoth.
细路,看 世上唯一一焦长毛象
I just heard you're going extinct.
辉烷，我匠讼你快要绝种
- You can't be two things. - She thinks you're a jerk.
- 英勇等於蚌春，和绵之不能混在一起 - 她说你是个笨蛋
Where's your big, happy family?
那你的开心大家庭呢? 我是最后一焦长毛象"
What's wrong with you?
你没事唉?
Manny, come on. We gotta go. Now!
文灶 ! 醒呀 ! 快点走 !
That way.
各稳
Do not leave your children unattended. All unattended children will be eaten.
请照顾同行的小朋友 失散的便会被我们吃掉
- Have you seen a mammoth? - No, sorry.
- 有昂到长毛象吗 9 -没有
-No.
- 有昂过长毛象吗 9 -我没有
Possum? About 11 foot tall?
网到成座山听大的问人条地吗9
- Hey, buddy, have you seen a mammoth? - I sure have. Big as life.
- 有昂过长毛象吗 9 - 当然有。棚棚如生
- Where? - I'm looking at him.
-在哪壬? - 我面前
Not me.
不是讼我
Poor guy doesn't know he's a mammoth.
可砷，自己是长毛象也不知
- 1 don't see her anywhere. - Maybe she's already on board.
- 找不到她 -或者她已上了船
Hurry, this way. Come on.
快点 ! 各稳 !
- There it is. - Ellie! Help!
- 就在那壬 ! - 救命啊 !
Come on, come on, run!
快点走 !
Push.
用力推 !
- You guys gotta go. - We're not leaving you.
- 你傅先走 - 我们不会于下你的
- I'm not asking. - Ellie, no.
- 别理我 ! - 爱莉
Ellie, don't worry. We're going for help.
爱莉，不要由 我们立即去找芝手 !
Stay here.
- 别走开 ! -没问题
- Help us. - Help! Somebody help.
- 救命 ! - 救命呀 !
- Help! - I'll save you.
- 救命 ! - 我来救你们 !
Great. Who's gonna save him?
好呀 ! 谁来救他?9
You really need to brush.
你真的要刷牙
OK, OK, OK. Jump in now.
好…跳下去 ' 跳 !
Come on, ‘fraidy cat. Come on.
跳啦 ! 扰采猫 ! 跳吧 !
You can do this, you can do this, you can do this.
你做得到的 !
Trust your instincts. Attack the water.
要台腾水 ! 我不是你的猎物
lam not your prey. I am not your prey.
我不是你的猎物 !
Attack the water. Stalking the prey.
我要偷竟猎物
Claw, kick. Even babies can do it. Come on.
搂水 ! 踢脚 ! 连BB都做得到
Hey. I'm stalking the prey.
我要偷竟猎物
You did it, buddy. You kicked water's butt.
老友 ' 你成功了。你打赢了水 !
Nothing to it. Most animals can swim as babies, you know.
很正常 ， 动物出生就懂得游水
Yeah, but not tigers. I left that part out.
对，但老虎例外。我讼漏了
There he is.
他们在那婉 !
Ellie, hold on to me.
爱莉，捉坦我 !
Manny, Manny, behind you.
辉熔 ! 和后面呀 !
There they are.
在那里 !
They made it.
他们成功了 !
We thought we'd never see you again.
还以为会再见不到你
We're gonna live.
我们有救了 !
We're gonna die.
我们有准了 !
- Well, I'm not leaving. - Grandpa, let go of the boat. The flood's over.
-我不走 ! -第和，放手吧 !
- This is my boat now. - Come on, let's go. Come on, come on.
- 各船是我的 -来，快点 ! 来吧 !
Stu. We made it. We're gonna live.
阿哪 ! 我们没事了 ! 我们死不了 !
Well, lam anyway.
至少我死不了
I'm thinking about starting a swim school.
我在考虑开班教游水
Sid's Squids.
【水怪森仔。
All hail Fire King.
拜见火和神
Hi.
喀
Fire King avert flood. Join us, O great and noble flaming one.
战腾洪水的火和神 领导我们吧，仿大而高足的火神
No, not so fast there, OK. You make a quality offer.
不，别那床急 你们的提议好吸引
But Fire King has a prior commitment. His herd needs him.
但火神有更重要的任务 我们好需要他
He is the gooey, sticky stuff that holds us together.
他那死织的性格 史我们粹得围结一起
He made this herd, and we'd be nothing without him.
他是我们不可缺少的成员 没有他“，我们会是一使散沙
- You mean it? - Sid. Sid.
你讼真的?
That doesn't mean "want to touch."
那不代表你可以揭我
Don't ask.
不准问
We're not the last ones anymore.
我们不是最后的两焦
You're not coming?
你还不来?了
You wanna go with them?
你想跟他们一起?9
lam a mammoth.
我是长毛象
I should probably be with a mammoth.
我应该跟长毛象一起
Don't you think?
你不同意吗 ?9
Unless?
除非?
I just wanna say...
我只想说…
I need to tell you...
我要告诉你…
Il hope you find everything you're looking for.
希望你找到真正想要的东西
You too.
你也一样
Manny, you've come a long way since we met and I'll take full credit for that,
全靠我教导 你已经比以前成熟很多
but you need to let go of the past so you can have a future.
但你必须忘记过去，才会有将来
- Go after her. - It's OK.
-跟她一骞走吧 -去吧
We'll always be here for you.
我们一定会支持你
-I'll keep in touch. - Yeah, yeah. You're a good friend.
- 保持联络 -对，老友记嘛
Point made. Now, go on. Scat.
心照，快点追吧 !
Our Manny's growing up.
我们的辉迷长大了
Ellie, l don't want us to be together because we have to.
爱莉 我想跟你一起不是因为走任
I want us to be together because we want to.
我想跟你一起 是因为我竹意你
And I wanna be with you, Ellie.
我喜坎跟你一起
- What do you say? - Manny, I thought you were going...
- 你甸得呢? - 文烷，我还以为…
You're possum enough for me.
不用再扮间人条鼎了
Well, it's just you and me now. Two bachelors knocking about in the wild.
现在只有我跟你了 两个王老五四图荡
Fine. But I'm not gonna carry you.
但你别妄想我会捕你
- I still have my pride, you know. - Come on, buddy, for old time's sake.
- 我还要面的 -来吧 , 老友，一场兄弟嘛 !
I'll carry him.
我捕他啦
- But your herd's leaving. - We are now.
- 但你的朋友要走了 - 我的朋友在各壬
Shotgun!
飞过去
Manny, who do you like better? Me or Diego?
文焊，你喜元我抑或大阿哥多一点
- Diego. It's not even close. - Told you.
- 大阿哥 ! 不用考上处 - 哈! 告诉过你啦
Manny, you can't choose between your kids.
文焊，不可以在孩子面前过样的
He's not my kid. Not even my dog.
他又不是我的纺子 连窒物都不如
If l had a dog and my dog had a kid and the dog's kid had a pet, that would be Sid.
如果我有和焦狗， 焦狗又有个仔 焦狗仔羡的宇物，就等如他
- Can I have a dog, Manny? -No.
- 辉焊我可以凌焦狗仔吗 ?9 -不
- Ellie, can I have a dog? - Of course you can, sweetie.
- 爱莉，我可以羡焦狗仔吗 ?9 - 当然得啦
Ellie, we have to be consistent with him.
爱莉，我们立场要一致
I saved you, little buddy.
小朋友，我救了你的命
Calm down. I saved you, little buddy. Remember?
冷静，是我救了你，训得吗 9